这里我们有一个冗余机器人的图像。
Here we have an image of a redundant robot.
这是我们在前一讲中介绍的概念。
And this is a concept that we introduced in the previous lecture.
这是一个具有非常大的自由度或关节​​的机器人。
This is a robot with a very large number of degrees of freedom or joints.
我们还介绍了任务空间和配置空间的概念。
We also introduced the concepts of task space and configuration space.
现在，这个机器人的任务空间是SE3的一个子集，这是完全相同的任务空间
Now the task space of this robot is a subset of SE3 and that's exactly the same task space
正如Puma机器人所拥有的那样，它在一个工作体积内，它可以移动到一个特定点
as the Puma robot has, that is within a working volume, it can move to a particular point
并实现特定的末端效应器方向。
and achieve a particular end effector orientation.
然而，这个机器人的配置空间要大得多。
However the configuration space of this robot is much, much bigger.
我们假设这个机器人有一百个关节，那么它的配置空间就是R.
We're assuming that this robot has got a hundred joints, then its configuration space is R
到了100，只有6个关节的Puma机器人，它有一个配置空间
to the 100, with a Puma robot with only 6 joints, it has got a configuration space of
R到6号。
R to the 6th.
任务空间的维度为6，配置空间有维度空间
The task space has got a dimension of 6, the configuration space has got a dimension space
100。
of 100.
因此，我们可以考虑使用这些自由度中的六个来控制位置
So we could consider that six of those degrees of freedom are used to control the position
和末端执行器的方向。
and orientation of the end effector.
其他94个自由度用于定义机器人手臂的任意形状，
The other 94 degrees of freedom are used to define an arbitrary shape for the robot arm,
这样我们就可以独立控制末端执行器的位置和方向
so that we can independently control the position and orientation of the end effector and the
手臂跟随的路径，以便从机器人的基座到达末端执行器。
path that the arm follows in order to get from the base of the robot to the end effector.
当谈到确定逆运动学时，我们遇到了一些问题;有
When it comes to determining the inverse kinematics then, we have a bit of a problem; there are
实际上是无限多组关节角度和无限数量的机器人配置
in fact an infinite number of sets of joint angles and infinite number of robot configurations
这将导致完全相同的末端效应器姿势。
that will lead to exactly the same end effector pose.
在Puma机器人的情况下，有六种配置给出相同的结束
In the case of the Puma robot, there were six configurations that gave the same end
效应器姿势;对于这个机器人，有一个无限的数字。
effector pose; for this robot there are an infinite number.
为了解决逆运动学问题，对于冗余机器人，我们必须依靠数值
To solve the inverse kinematics then for a redundant robot, we have to rely on a numerical
解。
solution.
我们现在要用冗余机器人做一个例子，我们将使用Toolbox模型
We're going to do an example now with a redundant robot and we're going to use a Toolbox model
称为MDLHyper3D。
called MDL Hyper 3D.
所以这是一个超级冗余机器人，有三个维度，我将要求一个20维的机器人。
So this is a Hyper-redundant robot, in 3 dimensions and I'm going to ask for a robot with 20 dimensions.
我们可以看到工作空间中有一个名为H3D的新串行链接对象
We can see that there is a new serial link object in the workspace called H3D and if
我们看一下机器人的参数，我们可以看到它有20个关节，每个关节
we look at the parameters of the robot, we can see that it has got 20 joints, each joint
只有0.05米长。
is only 0.05 meters long.
让我们用数字计算逆运动学，我们将应用ikine方法
Let's compute the inverse kinematics numerically and we're going to apply the ikine method
在那个特定的物体上，我将传递我想要机器人的姿势
on that particular object and I'm going to pass in the pose that I want the robot to
采用，我已经定义了，我将通过最初的关节角度
adopt, that I have already defined and I'm going to pass in the initial joint angles
我将使用工作空间变量QZ，它由创建的脚本定义
and I'm going to use the workspace variable QZ, that was defined by the script that created
我的机器人。
the robot for me.
在这里，我们有解决方案。
And here we have the solution.
我们计算了一个20元素向量，它是这个20所需的关节角度
We've computed a 20 element vector, which are the joint angles necessary for this 20
关节机器人采用姿势T2。
joint robot to adopt the pose T2.
我可以通过计算关节集的正向运动学来测试这种正确性
I can test the correctness of this by computing the forward Kinematics for the set of joint
我刚刚计算出的角度，它就是它的样子，这就是原始的姿势
angles that I just computed and that's what it looks like and this is the original pose
我要求的。
that I asked for.
所以我们可以看到它们是相同的。
So we can see that they are identical.
我可以在由计算出的关节角度集合中绘制机器人的配置
I can plot the configuration of the robot at the set of joint angles computed by the
反向运动学，它看起来像那样。
inverse kinematics and it looks something like that.
坚持下去，我现在可以叠加在我要求的原始姿势上，这是在工作区中
Hold on so I can overlay on that now the original pose that I asked for, which was in the workspace
变量T2。
variable T2.
在那里我们看到末端执行器处于正确位置并且它具有
And there we see that the end effector is in the correct position and that it has the
正确的方向。
correct orientation.